<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>newsletters on LaTeX Boilerplates</title>
    <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/tags/newsletters/</link>
    <description>Recent content in newsletters on LaTeX Boilerplates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://swiftlatex.github.io/tags/newsletters/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/posts/newsletters/professional-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/posts/newsletters/professional-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>Professional Newsletter Description: This elegant newsletter template is best suited to corporate or organizational newsletters with several large entries. It features space for a large wide header at the top with the company logo and information. The layout is highly modifiable and features the ability to include a sidebar encased in a border, an in-text box, quotation and single or multi-column text layouts in any configuration! The template makes extensive use of linking for quick reader browsing, a table of contents is present on the first page and links to every entry in the newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Three Column Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/posts/newsletters/short-three-column-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/posts/newsletters/short-three-column-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>Short Three Column Newsletter Description: This newsletter template is best suited to shorter newsletters consisting of short articles from a number of contributors. It features a prominent main news item at the start to provide a space for important updates or a summation of events by a single author. The body of the newsletter has a three-column layout which is conducive to short articles by a number of authors. The newsletter header on the first page clearly displays the newsletter name and edition while the footers on each page provide contact information and a longer description of the newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>