<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Curricula-vitaes on LaTeX Boilerplates</title>
    <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Curricula-vitaes on LaTeX Boilerplates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Resume/CV and Cover Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/awesome-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/awesome-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Awesome Resume/CV and Cover Letter Description: This gorgeous Resume/CV template comes with a matching cover letter template to help simplify the process of applying for your next job. Both templates feature a clean header listing your essential contact information and fields of expertise as well as a subtle matching footer. Clear sectioning within the resume/CV template ensures your achievements are easily navigated and extensively described by major heading, then minor heading, then sub-heading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cies Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/cies-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/cies-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Cies Resume/CV Description: This Resume/CV template features a compact information-rich layout suitable for a mid-career professional. A defining feature of the design is a relatively large block of two-column text at the start of the template to include a summary of interests, achievements, history, etc. This acts as a useful place to communicate information with the potential employer that may otherwise be overlooked by simply reading a list of achievements and job titles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classicthesis-Styled CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/classicthesis-styled-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/classicthesis-styled-cv/</guid>
      <description>Classicthesis-Styled CV Description: This template combines the Classicthesis style with the currvita document layout to create a beautiful CV/Résumé. The margin is moved to the left of the document and now holds employer names, degrees or descriptions which makes for quick reference by potential employers. Major headings are clearly separated as blocks within which each entry is styled with the date, title and description. The template is quite compact and manages to squeeze references and grades for courses into small blocks of text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compact Academic CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/compact-academic-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/compact-academic-cv/</guid>
      <description>Compact Academic CV Description: This curriculum vitae/resume template is designed to succinctly display your career information and works particularly well for showcasing academic careers. Academics tend to have many appointments, honours and publications which this template compresses down to single lines to maximise readability and minimise length. The design is minimalist with plenty of whitespace and a central feature of the template is the optional year labels for all entries in the CV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deedy Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/deedy-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/deedy-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Deedy Resume/CV Description: This Resume/CV template features a large header with your name and contact information clearly displayed. The Resume/CV content is then in a two-column layout which concentrates a large amount of information in a small space. This allows you to choose which aspects of your academic and professional life to focus on depending on their importance for the position you are applying for. Major sections and their subsections are strongly deviated to grab the attention of the hiring manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/developer-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/developer-cv/</guid>
      <description>Developer CV Description This curriculum vitae/resume template is tailored for software developers to display their skills and experience in a clean and simple way. The top of the template contains space for profiles and contact information on various platforms and uses familiar FontAwesome icons. Skills in various technologies and platforms are displayed at a glance in a skill bar chart and bubbles of varying sizes. Experience at different firms is listed in an ordered list and includes examples of technologies used at each position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freeman Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/freeman-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/freeman-cv/</guid>
      <description>Freeman Curriculum Vitae Description This curriculum vitae template fits a large amount of information in a concise two-column layout without feeling too saturated with information. When your content grows too large, it will be automatically wrapped to the next page, as you can see in the PDF preview. Sections are cleanly delimited and can be easily moved around to highlight the parts of your experience and skills that are most important to the job you are applying for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friggeri Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/friggeri-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/friggeri-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Friggeri Resume/CV Description: This beautiful Resume/CV template is suitable for anyone, from a designer with many short contracts to a scientist with varied publications. The template features a sidebar for important information such as contact details, languages, skills, titles, etc. The rest of the content is housed in clear colored sections with each entry featuring a space for a date, title, description and location. The publication list in this template is particularly useful for those that wish to list an extensive list of publications within separate categories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Professional CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/long-professional-curriculum-vitae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/long-professional-curriculum-vitae/</guid>
      <description>Long Professional CV Description: This curriculum vitae template is clearly structured with bold centered category names for each section. The descriptions of tasks for each job are in bullet points. This template is conducive to longer CVs since there is no aesthetic limit to how much information can be placed in each section. Would suit a professional in the mid- to late-stage of their career. Important note: The file ‘res.cls’ is required to be in the same directory as the template because the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medium Length Graduate CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/medium-length-graduate-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/medium-length-graduate-cv/</guid>
      <description>Medium Length Graduate CV Description: This curriculum vitae template has section headings on the left side of the document with section content on the right. Bullet points are used to separate different tasks within each job. This document layout makes this template more suited to a short or medium length curriculum vitae taking at most two pages. Would be best used by a recent graduate with limited experience looking for their first job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medium Length Professional</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/medium-length-professional-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/medium-length-professional-cv/</guid>
      <description>Medium Length Professional Description: This curriculum vitae template is clearly structured into sections separated by lines. As is, the template is more conducive to medium-length professional CV’s where work experience dominates the interest of the employer. The template can easily be expanded out to multiple pages but is best kept to at most 2 pages for section clarity. Important note: The file ‘resume.cls’ is required to be in the same directory as the template because the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ModernCV and Cover Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/moderncv-cv-and-cover-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/moderncv-cv-and-cover-letter/</guid>
      <description>ModernCV and Cover Letter Description: This template uses the ‘ModernCV’ class to create a multi-page CV and cover letter. The CV is clearly structured with large section titles and important dates on a sidebar. Contact information is clearly displayed in a gray block. This class features four document themes which completely change the layout of the document, to get a preview of each of these themes see the PDF previews below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twenty Seconds Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/twenty-seconds-resumecv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/twenty-seconds-resumecv/</guid>
      <description>Twenty Seconds Resume/CV Description: This simple Resume/CV template features a large sidebar with key information about you neatly presented for quick perusal. Your main skills can be quickly highlighted using progress bars ranging from novice to expert, this is particularly useful for programming languages and other skills where time is required for mastery. The template body is then presented delimited by large colored section titles (alternating gray and blue). Inside these, you can further divide content by subsection or simply write paragraphs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenneker Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/wenneker-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/wenneker-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Wenneker Resume/CV Description: This simple and clean Resume/CV template features a two column layout with your most important information displayed in the left column for immediate overview by potential employers. The right column houses the body of the document and begins with a large header containing your name, a subheading for your occupation and a short paragraph detailing your history and/or goals. The rest of the body is neatly divided into main sections with subsections in blue and further descriptions in plain text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wilson Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/wilson-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:33:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/curricula-vitae/wilson-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Wilson Resume/CV Description: This Resume/CV template features a spacious layout with a conservative style designed to clearly and simply put forward your work experience and information. The layout is most suited to longer CVs as job descriptions can be quite extensive and can be organized with bullet points or paragraphs of text. The inclusion of a personal profile allows you to succinctly state your career goals and achievements while the skills section lets you list large amounts of technical expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>