<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>articles on LaTeX Templates</title>
    <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/tags/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in articles on LaTeX Templates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 10:53:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/tags/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Arsclassica Article</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/arsclassica-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 10:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/arsclassica-article/</guid>
      <description>Arsclassica Article Description: This article uses the Arsclassica package (a modification of the Classic Thesis package) to specify the document layout and structure. The template features a single column layout which makes it suitable for a greater number of applications such as for academic articles, business articles and reports. The page layout is very clean and minimal to focus on the content at hand in an elegant way. Examples of virtually all typical article constituents are included: references, mathematics, lists, figures, tables, sections and theorems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal Article</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/journal-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 10:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/journal-article/</guid>
      <description>Journal Article Description: This article template aims to emulate scientific journal publications by using a conservative thin document style. The format of the template follows the typical journal publication including an abstract for summarizing the article, introduction, methods, results and discussion. Examples of an equation, table and list are included. Original Author: This article template was originally created by Frits Wenneker but has been extensively modified for this website by Vel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stylish Article</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/stylish-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 10:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/stylish-article/</guid>
      <description>Stylish Article Description: This article template attempts to emulate the design of contemporary scientific publications. It does this by including colored boxes behind the abstract and headings and a succinct text layout. The template features a table of contents, something usually not seen in articles, which makes it ideal for longer articles with significant structure or for archival purposes. This table of contents can be removed for a look more suited to journal publication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenneker Article</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/wenneker-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 10:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/wenneker-article/</guid>
      <description>Wenneker Article Description: This article template features a large eye-catching title section with space for multiple authors and affiliations per author. The article has a traditional two column layout to make content easy to read. An abstract section is present to provide a lead-in or summary of the article and features a large lettrine to further draw the reader’s eye. The template contains examples of sectioning, referencing, equations, tables, figures and lists to make it easy for you to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>