<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>laboratory-books on LaTeX Templates</title>
    <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/tags/laboratory-books/</link>
    <description>Recent content in laboratory-books on LaTeX Templates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 10:53:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/tags/laboratory-books/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Compact Laboratory Book</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/laboratory-books/compact-laboratory-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 10:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/laboratory-books/compact-laboratory-book/</guid>
      <description>Compact Laboratory Book Description: This template is useful for keeping track of progress made on different experiments in a laboratory. It features a compact layout for clean reading with each day clearly distinct from other days. Multiple experiments and sub-experiments can be cited for each day allowing the tracking of progress on multiple different avenues of research more easily. The template includes examples of a table, figure, equation, bibliography and citation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Laboratory Book</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/laboratory-books/daily-laboratory-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 10:53:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/laboratory-books/daily-laboratory-book/</guid>
      <description>Daily Laboratory Book Description: This template is useful for those working in a laboratory where records must be kept for academic or commercial purposes. Often times working in the laboratory means scrawling messy notes in a physical book so this template helps to make a laboratory book more organized and digitally searchable. The template features a cover page, hyperlinked table of contents, daily logs of progress made on individual experiments and a formulae and media recipes section.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>