<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>LaTeX Templates</title>
    <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/</link>
    <description>Recent content on LaTeX Templates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>a0poster Landscape Poster</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/conference-posters/a0poster-landscape-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/conference-posters/a0poster-landscape-poster/</guid>
      <description>a0poster Landscape Poster Description: This poster features a clean landscape layout with a large header section housing important information about the poster, a column for contact information and space for a logo of your institution or a photo of you. Poster content is neatly divided into four columns to make use of the space available as much as possible. The number of columns can easily be changed if you would like the extra width for larger tables and figures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a0poster Portrait Poster</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/conference-posters/a0poster-portrait-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/conference-posters/a0poster-portrait-poster/</guid>
      <description>a0poster Portrait Poster Description: This poster features a clean portrait layout with a large header section housing important information about the poster and space for a logo of your institution or a photo of you. Poster content is neatly divided into two columns which is typical for a poster with a portrait orientation. The number of columns can easily be changed if you would like more room for text. The template features the ability to easily change the color of any section or element and shows this off with several examples (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Title Page</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-title-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-title-page/</guid>
      <description>Academic Title Page Description: This title page is useful for academic works such as assignments, reports, theses or books. The headings can be used to neatly display the institute, course or subject matter of the work. It design is clean with the major feature being two horizontal lines highlighting the title. The template contains code for an alternate layout without a supervisor name and for an institution logo at the bottom of the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACS Publications</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/acs-publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/acs-publications/</guid>
      <description>ACS Publications Description: American Chemical Society (ACS) Publications allows authors to submit their manuscripts formatted in LaTeX to any of their journals. For this, they provide a demo template which contains the structure and reference style they would like for submissions. The demo template provided here includes the achemso class, bibliography style, documentation and an example template with associated bibliography. While the demo template is extensively commented, any additional configuration options you need or problems you may experience are likely to be solved by reading the included achemso.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Geophysical Union</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/american-geophysical-union/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/american-geophysical-union/</guid>
      <description>American Geophysical Union Description The American Geophysical Union (AGU) allows authors to submit their manuscript formatted in LaTeX to any of their journals. For this, they provide a template which contains the structure and reference style they would like for submissions. The template contains two tex files, one for the article and another for supporting information. The AGU LaTeX template features a single-column draft layout by default. The template contains ample commenting which advises you how the AGU would like you to use the template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME)</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/asme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/asme/</guid>
      <description>American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) Description: The American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) allows authors to submit their manuscripts formatted in LaTeX to any of their journals and conferences. For this, they provide three templates which contain the structure and referencing style they would like for submissions. If you are submitting a journal article for initial review, you should use the two-column journal template; if your journal article has been accepted then you should use the one-column journal template for production purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arsclassica Article</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/arsclassica-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/arsclassica-article/</guid>
      <description>Arsclassica Article Description: This article uses the Arsclassica package (a modification of the Classic Thesis package) to specify the document layout and structure. The template features a single column layout which makes it suitable for a greater number of applications such as for academic articles, business articles and reports. The page layout is very clean and minimal to focus on the content at hand in an elegant way. Examples of virtually all typical article constituents are included: references, mathematics, lists, figures, tables, sections and theorems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article Notes</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/article-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/article-notes/</guid>
      <description>Article Notes Description: This template is for academics and students wishing to make notes on academic articles for future reference or distribution. It is ideal for long-term preservation of thoughts on any given publication and lets you easily specify the information of the article as well as when the notes were made and last revised. Sections within the template can be populated with your notes on the theoretical background, methods, results and discussion/conclusions of the article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/acm-publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/acm-publications/</guid>
      <description>Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) Description: The Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) allows authors to submit their manuscripts formatted in LaTeX to any of their journals. For this, they provide templates which contain the structure and referencing style they would like for submissions. For the vast majority of ACM journals, you should use the Small Standard Format Template, however, a few require one of the other templates, so find the journal you are submitting to in the list below to identify the template you should use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Resume/CV and Cover Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/awesome-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/awesome-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Awesome Resume/CV and Cover Letter Description: This gorgeous Resume/CV template comes with a matching cover letter template to help simplify the process of applying for your next job. Both templates feature a clean header listing your essential contact information and fields of expertise as well as a subtle matching footer. Clear sectioning within the resume/CV template ensures your achievements are easily navigated and extensively described by major heading, then minor heading, then sub-heading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>baposter Landscape Poster</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/conference-posters/baposter-landscape-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/conference-posters/baposter-landscape-poster/</guid>
      <description>baposter Landscape Poster Description: This poster template features a large header with space for two logos to either side of the title and neatly divides poster content into separate boxes with clear headings in each one. The landscape layout features four columns which can be merged into larger blocks if required, such as in the Results 1, Conclusion and Future Research sections of the template. Merged blocks allow more space for showing off results while blocks taking up one column are ideal for small paragraphs of text or details about the research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>baposter Portrait Poster</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/conference-posters/baposter-portrait-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/conference-posters/baposter-portrait-poster/</guid>
      <description>baposter Portrait Poster Description: This poster template neatly divides content into separate boxes with clear headings in each one. The portrait layout features a small side column for study details and a larger column to show off results obtained from the research. The larger column can be optionally divided into two columns to squeeze more information into the poster. The default colors of the template are in the blue spectrum but can be easily changed within the template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beamer Presentation</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/presentations/beamer-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/presentations/beamer-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Beamer Presentation Description: This presentation template uses the well-known Beamer class and shows how effortless presentation-making with LaTeX can be. The template has examples of most of the features that are typically found in a presentation, including the following example slides: title, overview, paragraphs of text, bullet points, blocks of highlighted text, multiple columns, tables, theorems, verbatim text, figures, citations, references and conclusions/acknowledgments. Examples of how to use sections and subsections show how a presentation can be broken down into distinct pieces for automatic inclusion on the overview slide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Forces Memo</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/canadian-forces-memo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/canadian-forces-memo/</guid>
      <description>Canadian Forces Memo Description: This template is for producing a memorandum (memo) within the Canadian Forces. It was made by using the Military Writing Guide provided for K. Thomas by his MCpl. Following many terrible experiences of having a memo come back with formatting adjustments required, he decided to come up with a template that will for the most part print a correctly-formatted memo with little need to make tweaks by the user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>Cheatsheet Description: This template is for creating a single page cheatsheet. Cheatsheets act as a reference for shortcuts in an application but can also be used as a reference for commands, symbols, functions, equations and any other use case where there are many ways to do something. The template features a three column layout to pack in a large amount of information into the single page. Each column is further subdivided by headings and blocks of similar commands are separated by spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Equations</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/chemical-equations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/chemical-equations/</guid>
      <description>Chemical Equations Description: This template provides a quick reference for typesetting chemical equations in LaTeX using the mhchem package which has been specifically designed to make chemical typesetting intuitive. The template starts with simple chemical notation and progresses to complex chemical equations involving a variety of interactions and notations. Original Author: The chemical equations in this template come from the mhchem bundle documentation by Martin Hensel. Open this template in SwiftLaTeX</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cies Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/cies-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/cies-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Cies Resume/CV Description: This Resume/CV template features a compact information-rich layout suitable for a mid-career professional. A defining feature of the design is a relatively large block of two-column text at the start of the template to include a summary of interests, achievements, history, etc. This acts as a useful place to communicate information with the potential employer that may otherwise be overlooked by simply reading a list of achievements and job titles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic Lined Title Page</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/classic-lined-title-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/classic-lined-title-page/</guid>
      <description>Classic Lined Title Page Description: This title page template features a classic lined look most suited to a book or other larger work. The title is highlighted with large red all-caps text and a thin rule underneath separates it from the author name and publisher further down the page. For a less intense look, a diversity of colours are available for selection, see here for a full list with examples. The template compiles as a standalone document to act as a starting point for creating a document but it includes instructions for integrating this title page into an existing document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classicthesis Typographic Thesis</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/theses/classicthesis-typographic-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/theses/classicthesis-typographic-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Classicthesis Typographic Thesis Description: This template has been designed as a homage to the elements of typographic style. As such, it has an air of efficiency and optimal design. It is suitable for any high-level degree thesis such as for a PhD, Masters or Honors. Sections within the thesis are clearly separated in a consistent way, as are sections within each chapter. The default structure of the thesis proceeds in the following order: title page, dedication, abstract, publications, acknowledgements, contents, list of tables/figures/listings, acronyms, content chapters, appendices, bibliography, colophon and declaration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classicthesis-Styled CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/classicthesis-styled-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/classicthesis-styled-cv/</guid>
      <description>Classicthesis-Styled CV Description: This template combines the Classicthesis style with the currvita document layout to create a beautiful CV/Résumé. The margin is moved to the left of the document and now holds employer names, degrees or descriptions which makes for quick reference by potential employers. Major headings are clearly separated as blocks within which each entry is styled with the date, title and description. The template is quite compact and manages to squeeze references and grades for courses into small blocks of text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleese Assignment</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/assignments/cleese-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/assignments/cleese-assignment/</guid>
      <description>Cleese Assignment Description This template comes in two versions, one for teachers/instructors/educators to create assignments/homework for their students to fill out by hand, and another for students proficient in LaTeX to answer questions posed to them at school or university/college. Both versions contain simple environments for each question and subquestion within, and allow answer boxes to be created with either an answer or blank for space to write an answer. Sets of questions can be grouped by headings and the template includes examples of including an image, table, equation and code within questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Snippet</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/code-snippet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/code-snippet/</guid>
      <description>Code Snippet Description: Often times it is useful to include some code in a document, either as an example or to display it for publication. This template simplifies the process of including code from virtually any programming language in a LaTeX document. It uses the listings package to create a box around a piece of code and allows a large number of well-commented customizations to change its appearance. The template also defines a custom command to include your code from a separate file, making the body of your document much cleaner than if you had pasted the code directly in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compact Academic CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/compact-academic-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/compact-academic-cv/</guid>
      <description>Compact Academic CV Description: This curriculum vitae/resume template is designed to succinctly display your career information and works particularly well for showcasing academic careers. Academics tend to have many appointments, honours and publications which this template compresses down to single lines to maximise readability and minimise length. The design is minimalist with plenty of whitespace and a central feature of the template is the optional year labels for all entries in the CV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compact Laboratory Book</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/laboratory-books/compact-laboratory-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/laboratory-books/compact-laboratory-book/</guid>
      <description>Compact Laboratory Book Description: This template is useful for keeping track of progress made on different experiments in a laboratory. It features a compact layout for clean reading with each day clearly distinct from other days. Multiple experiments and sub-experiments can be cited for each day allowing the tracking of progress on multiple different avenues of research more easily. The template includes examples of a table, figure, equation, bibliography and citation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Booklet</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/conference-booklet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/conference-booklet/</guid>
      <description>Conference Booklet Description This template is for conference organisers who wish to produce a booklet or online document for attendees detailing conference information and presenters. The template is primarily aimed at academic conferences but can be tailored to commercial conferences. The template is structured to initially display a cover page (from image) then the main conference information. A daily timetable follows and breaks down each day into conference events, breaks and talks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference/Event Timetable</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/calendars/conference-event-timetable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/calendars/conference-event-timetable/</guid>
      <description>Conference/Event Timetable Description: This calendar template is useful for creating a conference/event calendar. Each day can be given a title (such as your location on that day) followed by the plan for that day. The calendar can span any number of weeks and the starting dates can be changed. Important note: The file ‘calendar.sty’ is required to be in the same directory as the template because the .tex file uses this custom style for structuring the calendar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contract</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/contract/</guid>
      <description>Contract Description: This template is for creating a contract with static and dynamic content. It is designed such that you add your static contract terms to the template once and re-use it for many clients using a number of dynamic variables, such as for the payee’s name and the hourly rate. The contract terms in this template are for a web design contract and are merely to provide an example of the structure your contract terms may follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Class</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/custom-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/custom-class/</guid>
      <description>Custom Class Description: This template is for advanced users of LaTeX who are interested in creating their own LaTeX class. The creation of a LaTeX class allows one to specify all document requirements (packages, input files, etc) and layout specifications in a .cls file while reserving the .tex file purely for content. An important feature of this template is the inclusion of a pair of custom class options which act as a toggle within the class to change document settings based on the class option supplied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Laboratory Book</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/laboratory-books/daily-laboratory-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/laboratory-books/daily-laboratory-book/</guid>
      <description>Daily Laboratory Book Description: This template is useful for those working in a laboratory where records must be kept for academic or commercial purposes. Often times working in the laboratory means scrawling messy notes in a physical book so this template helps to make a laboratory book more organized and digitally searchable. The template features a cover page, hyperlinked table of contents, daily logs of progress made on individual experiments and a formulae and media recipes section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deedy Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/deedy-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/deedy-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Deedy Resume/CV Description: This Resume/CV template features a large header with your name and contact information clearly displayed. The Resume/CV content is then in a two-column layout which concentrates a large amount of information in a small space. This allows you to choose which aspects of your academic and professional life to focus on depending on their importance for the position you are applying for. Major sections and their subsections are strongly deviated to grab the attention of the hiring manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/developer-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/developer-cv/</guid>
      <description>Developer CV Description This curriculum vitae/resume template is tailored for software developers to display their skills and experience in a clean and simple way. The top of the template contains space for profiles and contact information on various platforms and uses familiar FontAwesome icons. Skills in various technologies and platforms are displayed at a glance in a skill bar chart and bubbles of varying sizes. Experience at different firms is listed in an ordered list and includes examples of technologies used at each position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diaz Essay</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/essays/diaz-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/essays/diaz-essay/</guid>
      <description>Diaz Essay Description This essay template is best used for literature essays containing mostly text. This is supported by a thin single column layout with clear unnumbered section titles to increase readability. The template contains an abstract, keywords and references, which makes it suitable for college/university essays but these elements can be easily removed for a simpler high school essay. Further examples of common essay components are included: referencing using a bibliography, an inline figure, a table and lists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dictionary</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/dictionary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/dictionary/</guid>
      <description>Dictionary Description: This template creates a dictionary with a two-column layout and clear headings delimiting different letters. The header on each page contains the first and last word on that page, making for easy navigation. Converting your current dictionary information to use in this template is easy as a single command specifies the addition of each word. By default, this line has four arguments for the: word, pronunciation, classification and definition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dreuw &amp; Deselaer’s Poster</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/conference-posters/dreuw-deselaers-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/conference-posters/dreuw-deselaers-poster/</guid>
      <description>Dreuw &amp;amp; Deselaer’s Poster Description: This poster template features a dark gray color scheme for content and a contrasting title and footer to highlight important information about the research. Content is laid out in two columns in a portrait orientation but changing it to landscape and increasing the number of columns is quite easy. The template makes extensive use of lists for styling which promotes a clear and concise description of research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eBook</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/books/ebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/books/ebook/</guid>
      <description>eBook Description: This ebook template is for those wishing to create a book in a format that is easily readable on electronic screens. To facilitate this, the template features a layout with narrow margins and a large font size to use as much of your screen real estate as possible. Each page features a header with the author and title of the book, as well as a page count at the bottom to indicate progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elmueller Formal Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/formal-letters/full-size-formal-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/formal-letters/full-size-formal-letter/</guid>
      <description>Elmueller Formal Letter Description: This formal letter template uses the ‘scrlttr2’ class to structure the letter for mailing with a special section for the addressee designed for windowed envelopes. The letter content is wide and fills the entire page with ample spacing between paragraphs for easy reading. Original Author: This formal letter was originally created by Micha Elmueller but has been extensively modified for this website. Open this template in SwiftLaTeX</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elsevier’s elsarticle Document Class</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/elseviers-elsarticle-document-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/elseviers-elsarticle-document-class/</guid>
      <description>Elsevier’s elsarticle Document Class Description: Elsevier’s elsarticle document class and templates can be used by academics to write and submit journal articles to all Elsevier journals. There are presently over 2,700 journals published by Elsevier with over 250,000 articles published per year. Popular journals include Cell, The Lancet, Lancet Infectious Diseases and Lancet Neurology but a complete list of all Elsevier journals can be found here. Elsevier explicitly state that this class and templates are their preferred format for articles submitted to all of their journals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Calculation Paper</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/engineering-calculation-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/engineering-calculation-paper/</guid>
      <description>Engineering Calculation Paper Description: This template for engineering calculation paper is designed for engineers to present calculations in a clear way for review or documentation purposes. The large header includes meta-information about the document for easy tracking and includes space for a company or university logo. The large main box allows clear presentation of calculations with the aid of sections and subsections. A large margin is present to the right of the main calculations for comments or notes about calculations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancyslides Presentation</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/presentations/fancyslides-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/presentations/fancyslides-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Fancyslides Presentation Description: This presentation template uses the Fancyslides class which builds on top of the well-known beamer class to give it a modern and concise design. The template is very minimalist with large font sizes and little space for text and would thus be suited for popular presentations by confident speakers. It makes extensive use of background images for slides to provide a strong visual counterpart to the verbal presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formal Book Title Page</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/formal-book-title-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/formal-book-title-page/</guid>
      <description>Formal Book Title Page Description: This title page template is best suited to books and formal applications, such as in the fields of science or engineering. It features a formal layout with a clear title highlighted by two horizontal rules. A subtitle is available to further describe the work and multiple authors/editors are catered for towards the centre of the page. The template compiles as a standalone document to act as a starting point for creating a document but it includes instructions for integrating this title page into an existing document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fphw Assignment</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/assignments/fphw-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/assignments/fphw-assignment/</guid>
      <description>fphw Assignment Description This template is for formatting assignments or homework in a clear and simple way. The title section at the top of the first page clearly displays the assignment, student and class information. This information also appears in the headers and footers of subsequent pages. Questions in the assignment are clearly demarcated and appear inside boxes to focus attention. The template features examples of including images, tables, equations and code listings for covering virtually all common assignment information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freeman Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/freeman-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/freeman-cv/</guid>
      <description>Freeman Curriculum Vitae Description This curriculum vitae template fits a large amount of information in a concise two-column layout without feeling too saturated with information. When your content grows too large, it will be automatically wrapped to the next page, as you can see in the PDF preview. Sections are cleanly delimited and can be easily moved around to highlight the parts of your experience and skills that are most important to the job you are applying for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/frequently-asked-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/frequently-asked-questions/</guid>
      <description>Frequently Asked Questions Description: This template provides an easy framework for creating a frequently asked questions (FAQ’s) document. The first page features a large title followed by a subtitle and list of all questions. Questions are clearly displayed in colored boxes with answers after them in plain text. Each question can contain a unique label to allow referencing it in future questions via links. Questions are also automatically numbered and this number can be referred to at any point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friggeri Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/friggeri-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/friggeri-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Friggeri Resume/CV Description: This beautiful Resume/CV template is suitable for anyone, from a designer with many short contracts to a scientist with varied publications. The template features a sidebar for important information such as contact details, languages, skills, titles, etc. The rest of the content is housed in clear colored sections with each entry featuring a space for a date, title, description and location. The publication list in this template is particularly useful for those that wish to list an extensive list of publications within separate categories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to submit a new template?</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/submit/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/submit/</guid>
      <description>The website is hosted in https://github.com/SwiftLaTeX/LaTeXBoilerPlate. Send a pull request or create a new issue to submit your template. Thanks </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/ieee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/ieee/</guid>
      <description>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) Description: The Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) allows authors to submit their publications formatted in LaTeX to any of their 100+ transactions journals except for IEEE Transactions on Dielectrics and Electrical Insulation. For this, they provide the IEEEtran class and demo templates which contain the structure and reference style they would like for submissions. The IEEE Photonics Society also provides the IEEEphot class and a demo template for submissions to IEEE Photonics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invoice</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/invoice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/invoice/</guid>
      <description>Invoice Description: This invoice template allows a small business or individual to produce invoices for goods and services. It features a clear header including the company providing the invoice followed by the recipient’s information. The list of goods and services being charged for is clear and concise separated by individual days and categories. The ability to include one-off expenses (without an hourly rate) is also present. The template is very simple to fill out; for each line a date, the number of hours worked and the hourly rate are specified and the template does all the calculations to produce the subtotal and total.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jacobs Landscape Poster</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/conference-posters/jacobs-landscape-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/conference-posters/jacobs-landscape-poster/</guid>
      <description>Jacobs Landscape Poster Description: This poster template features a clean sectioned look suitable for presenting research at a conference. Important information is highlighted with colored boxes and each section within the poster is clearly separated from the others. The layout of the template contains four columns but this can be changed to accommodate varying amounts of information or figures. Examples of a table, figure, equation, list and bibliography are present in the template to provide a starting point for any requirement you may have for your own poster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal Article</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/journal-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/journal-article/</guid>
      <description>Journal Article Description: This article template aims to emulate scientific journal publications by using a conservative thin document style. The format of the template follows the typical journal publication including an abstract for summarizing the article, introduction, methods, results and discussion. Examples of an equation, table and list are included. Original Author: This article template was originally created by Frits Wenneker but has been extensively modified for this website by Vel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kaobook</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/books/kaobook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/books/kaobook/</guid>
      <description>kaobook Description This template is designed for writing books and graduate-level theses and provides numerous examples and documentation to enable complex requirements. The design features a relatively narrow main text column with an adjacent wide margin to house notes, figures, tables, citations and captions. The narrow text column facilitates faster reading by reducing horizontal eye movement distance and makes reading less fatiguing. Content can be split into the standard section types of parts, chapters, sections, subsections, subsubsections and paragraphs with examples of all of these provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kaobook</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/theses/kaobook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/theses/kaobook/</guid>
      <description>kaobook Description This template is designed for writing books and graduate-level theses and provides numerous examples and documentation to enable complex requirements. The design features a relatively narrow main text column with an adjacent wide margin to house notes, figures, tables, citations and captions. The narrow text column facilitates faster reading by reducing horizontal eye movement distance and makes reading less fatiguing. Content can be split into the standard section types of parts, chapters, sections, subsections, subsubsections and paragraphs with examples of all of these provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KOMA-Script Presentation</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/presentations/koma-script-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/presentations/koma-script-presentation/</guid>
      <description>KOMA-Script Presentation Description: This presentation template is unique in that it uses the standard KOMA-Script scrartcl class to create a beautiful presentation. The use of a standard class means that this template allows direct copy/pasting from other LaTeX documents and doesn’t require specialized commands like other presentation classes. The design of the slides is focused on readability with large fonts and line spacing. Each slide features a running head and a footer with information about the author as well as progress through the presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lachaise Assignment</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/assignments/lachaise-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/assignments/lachaise-assignment/</guid>
      <description>Lachaise Assignment Description This template is for teachers/instructors/educators to create assignments/homework for their students. It includes a clear title on the first page for the course, assignment and teacher’s name, as well as the institution and date. Sets of questions can be grouped by headings and the template includes examples of unnumbered and numbered sections, and numbered subsections (for longer assignments). Amongst the description text for each question, examples are provided for virtually any subject matter, including: equations, algorithms, code and command line outputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter of Notice</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/formal-letters/letter-of-notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/formal-letters/letter-of-notice/</guid>
      <description>Letter of Notice Description: This formal letter template is specifically tailored to provide a short notice to the addressee. The large heading bar at the top provides a central focus for the letter while the body of the letter is intentionally narrow, centered and in an 11pt font size with increased spacing to restrict the text of the letter to a single sharp message. This template would be most suited to a short formal communication of notice between a client and a business, such as for a notice of inspection, resignation letter or a letter stating intent to move out of a property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Lined Cover Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/cover-letters/long-lined-cover-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/cover-letters/long-lined-cover-letter/</guid>
      <description>Long Lined Cover Letter Description: This cover letter template uses the newlfm package and features a clean professional layout which can take a large amount of text per page. The ability to include a company/institution logo at the top of the letter further adds to the professional look. The content of the letter itself is presented between two horizontal lines and contains your contact information, the addressee and letter content. Any element of the letter can be easily removed within the template to customize the layout to your requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Professional CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/long-professional-curriculum-vitae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/long-professional-curriculum-vitae/</guid>
      <description>Long Professional CV Description: This curriculum vitae template is clearly structured with bold centered category names for each section. The descriptions of tasks for each job are in bullet points. This template is conducive to longer CVs since there is no aesthetic limit to how much information can be placed in each section. Would suit a professional in the mid- to late-stage of their career. Important note: The file ‘res.cls’ is required to be in the same directory as the template because the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maggi Memoir Thesis</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/theses/maggi-memoir-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/theses/maggi-memoir-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Maggi Memoir Thesis Description: This template uses the memoir document class to beautifully typeset a thesis. It is suitable for any high-level degree thesis such as for a PhD, Masters or Honors. The layout of the content is in a thin format to promote easy reading and the template features advanced specification of margins and trimming. An example of this is seen in the trimming lines within the preview for this template whereby the stock paper size and the size of the content are independently specified within the template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masters/Doctoral Thesis</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/theses/masters-doctoral-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/theses/masters-doctoral-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Masters/Doctoral Thesis Description This template provides a full framework for writing a graduate level thesis. It is carefully structured and separated into multiple parts for easy editing. Included are the following pages/sections: a cover page, declaration of authorship, quotation, abstract, acknowledgements, contents page(s), list of figures, list of tables, abbreviations, physical constants, symbols, dedication, example chapter, example appendix and bibliography. An example chapter is included which explains the basics of LaTeX and this template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medium Length Graduate CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/medium-length-graduate-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/medium-length-graduate-cv/</guid>
      <description>Medium Length Graduate CV Description: This curriculum vitae template has section headings on the left side of the document with section content on the right. Bullet points are used to separate different tasks within each job. This document layout makes this template more suited to a short or medium length curriculum vitae taking at most two pages. Would be best used by a recent graduate with limited experience looking for their first job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medium Length Professional</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/medium-length-professional-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/medium-length-professional-cv/</guid>
      <description>Medium Length Professional Description: This curriculum vitae template is clearly structured into sections separated by lines. As is, the template is more conducive to medium-length professional CV’s where work experience dominates the interest of the employer. The template can easily be expanded out to multiple pages but is best kept to at most 2 pages for section clarity. Important note: The file ‘resume.cls’ is required to be in the same directory as the template because the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memo</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/memo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/memo/</guid>
      <description>Memo Description: A memo (formal name memorandum) is a business document used for communication within a company or between two companies. Their purpose is to convey information in a relatively short but formal document which can be sent out to a number of relevant people. This template uses the texMemo class to make writing a memo using LaTeX incredibly simple. The template includes the ability to include a company logo underneath which the memo information is housed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimalist Book Title Page</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/minimalist-book-title-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/minimalist-book-title-page/</guid>
      <description>Minimalist Book Title Page Description: This title page template is best suited for a book. The minimalistic design immediately highlights the title and the use of red further focuses the eye on the core of what the work is about. The subtitle is neatly tucked away under the title to expand on it and the author/publisher information frames the title. A diversity of colours are available for the title, see here for a full list with examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ModernCV and Cover Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/moderncv-cv-and-cover-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/moderncv-cv-and-cover-letter/</guid>
      <description>ModernCV and Cover Letter Description: This template uses the ‘ModernCV’ class to create a multi-page CV and cover letter. The CV is clearly structured with large section titles and important dates on a sidebar. Contact information is clearly displayed in a gray block. This class features four document themes which completely change the layout of the document, to get a preview of each of these themes see the PDF previews below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monthly Calendar</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/calendars/monthly-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/calendars/monthly-calendar/</guid>
      <description>Monthly Calendar Description: This calendar template is useful for creating a calendar month on a single A4 sheet of paper. This can be left blank with just the day numbers or text can be written for individual days. The starting day and date can be readily changed within the template. LaTeX is not made for easily numbering calendars and automatically adjusting to different needs. This means this template can be a bit finicky but it has been extensively commented to make it as easy as possible to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Purpose Large Font</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/multi-purpose-large-font-title-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/multi-purpose-large-font-title-page/</guid>
      <description>Multi-Purpose Large Font Description: This title page template can be used for almost any document type. The title is displayed in a very large font size in a wide grey box to accentuate the subject matter while your details are shown at the bottom in a small section. The box colour can be changed from grey and the template includes a secondary serif font option. This template compiles as a standalone document to act as a starting point for creating a document but it includes instructions for integrating the title page into an existing document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIH Grant Proposal</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/nih-grant-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/nih-grant-proposal/</guid>
      <description>NIH Grant Proposal Description: The National Institutes of Health (NIH) provides grants to researchers wishing to fund their research projects. The lengthy application requires a great deal of information regarding the proposed research and this template is meant to make the process easier by creating the document structure required for the application and providing examples of typical content. The template is primarily meant for the Specific Aims, Research Plan and Bibliography sections of the grant application but other parts (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plain Cover Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/cover-letters/plain-cover-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/cover-letters/plain-cover-letter/</guid>
      <description>Plain Cover Letter Description: A plain cover letter template with your name and address at the top in bold. The layout is traditional and is best suited to single-page letters. The format offers plenty of space for a longer cover letter and includes a description of the content that should be written in each paragraph. Original Author: This cover letter was originally created by the Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute but has been extensively modified for this website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PNAS Journal</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/pnas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/pnas/</guid>
      <description>PNAS Journal Description: The Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America (PNAS) allows authors to submit their manuscript formatted in LaTeX to the PNAS Journal. For this, they provide a template which contains the structure and reference style they would like for submissions. The PNAS LaTeX template features a two-column layout and mirrors the layout seen in final publications released by PNAS. This allows authors to determine the exact length of their manuscripts as they will appear if accepted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poems</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/poems/</guid>
      <description>Poems Description: This template typesets your poetry in a beautiful and simple way using the ‘verse’ LaTeX package and a number of custom commands. The template is designed for you to quickly typeset poetry without worrying about complex indentation and positioning. Most of the functionality of the package is included in the template including: automatic poem positioning based on average verse length, custom title/author commands, line numbering, every second line indentation, indentation patterns and manual indentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Press Release</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/press-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/press-release/</guid>
      <description>Press Release Description: A press release is a written statement to the media. Press releases are used to announce news, products, services, events, awards, etc. Writing a descriptive press release is a crucial requirement of PR and communication work. This template makes writing a press release easy by dividing the document into the necessary sections and elements that are required for a clear press release. At the top of the press release is a place for a logo for your company/institution which serves to give the release credibility and recognition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional Formal Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/formal-letters/professional-formal-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/formal-letters/professional-formal-letter/</guid>
      <description>Professional Formal Letter Description: This formal letter template is suitable for individuals representing a professional institution such as a university, company or organization. This is most evident in the large header at the top of the letter where there is space for a logo and a large institution name along with your name and title. A block for your information is neatly tucked away underneath the header line on the right with a vertically-overlapping block for the addressee information underneath on the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/newsletters/professional-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/newsletters/professional-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>Professional Newsletter Description: This elegant newsletter template is best suited to corporate or organizational newsletters with several large entries. It features space for a large wide header at the top with the company logo and information. The layout is highly modifiable and features the ability to include a sidebar encased in a border, an in-text box, quotation and single or multi-column text layouts in any configuration! The template makes extensive use of linking for quick reader browsing, a table of contents is present on the first page and links to every entry in the newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional Table</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/professional-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/professional-table/</guid>
      <description>Professional Table Description: This table template provides a quick reference for how to add professional-looking tables to any document. The booktabs package is utilized to enable the use of horizontal rules specific for different parts of the table, adding to the overall professional aesthetic of the table. The table includes examples of amalgamating multiple columns into one cell and creating horizontal rules which do not span the entire width of the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Library of Science (PLOS)</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/public-library-of-science-plos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/public-library-of-science-plos/</guid>
      <description>Public Library of Science (PLOS) Description: The Public Library of Science (PLOS) allows authors to submit their manuscript formatted in LaTeX to any of their journals. For this, they provide a template which contains the structure and reference style they would like for submissions. Journals published by PLOS include: PLOS ONE, PLOS Biology, PLOS Medicine, PLOS Computational Biology, PLOS Genetics, PLOS Pathogens, PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases and PLOS Currents. The PLOS LaTeX template features an intentionally simple layout to make review easy and PLOS explicitly state that template elements should not be modified or removed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royal Society of Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/royal-society-of-chemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/royal-society-of-chemistry/</guid>
      <description>Royal Society of Chemistry Description The Royal Society of Chemistry provides two LaTeX templates for authors to submit articles and communications to all journals they publish. Each template includes dummy content which provides an example for authors for how to write their paper in LaTeX. At the submission stage, author(s) are requested to provide a PDF of the manuscript typeset in LaTeX including all figures as well as the LaTeX files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science Journal</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/science-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/academic-journals/science-journal/</guid>
      <description>Science Journal Description: The Science Journal allows authors to submit their manuscripts formatted in LaTeX. For this, they provide a template which contains the structure and reference style they would like for submissions. The template provided here includes a filled-out example article, the Science bibliography style, example bibliography and the scicite package used for formatting the reference numbers. The template is extensively commented and sectioned to make writing your Science manuscript easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Stylish Cover Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/cover-letters/short-stylish-cover-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/cover-letters/short-stylish-cover-letter/</guid>
      <description>Short Stylish Cover Letter Description: This stylish cover letter includes a custom large header and footer. The ‘To’ address is placed so as to show up in a windowed envelope. Unfortunately these do not leave much space for text but there are several ways of increasing available space described in the template. Important notes: this template needs to be compiled with XeLaTeX. There should be a setting in your LaTeX distribution to change to XeLaTeX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Three Column Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/newsletters/short-three-column-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/newsletters/short-three-column-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>Short Three Column Newsletter Description: This newsletter template is best suited to shorter newsletters consisting of short articles from a number of contributors. It features a prominent main news item at the start to provide a space for important updates or a summation of events by a single author. The body of the newsletter has a three-column layout which is conducive to short articles by a number of authors. The newsletter header on the first page clearly displays the newsletter name and edition while the footers on each page provide contact information and a longer description of the newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stylish Article</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/stylish-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/stylish-article/</guid>
      <description>Stylish Article Description: This article template attempts to emulate the design of contemporary scientific publications. It does this by including colored boxes behind the abstract and headings and a succinct text layout. The template features a table of contents, something usually not seen in articles, which makes it ideal for longer articles with significant structure or for archival purposes. This table of contents can be removed for a look more suited to journal publication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stylish Title Page</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/stylish-title-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/stylish-title-page/</guid>
      <description>Stylish Title Page Description: This title page template features a large title and subtitle surrounded by two curly brackets to bring focus to the title and add to the stylish design of the template. The author name is centered below the title and publisher information is seen at the bottom. This makes the template best suited to a book or other large work, but it can be easily adapted to any other usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Legrand Orange Book</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/books/the-legrand-orange-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/books/the-legrand-orange-book/</guid>
      <description>The Legrand Orange Book Description: This book template features an elegant layout with a beautiful title page and part/chapter headings. The book itself is highly structured into parts, chapters, sections and then subsections. Each is numbered and these numbers are prominently displayed in the left margin where each begins as well as in page headers. Sections and subsections also appear as mini tables of contents on pages separating parts of the book to provide an outline of the content to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wiley Book Style</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/books/wiley-book-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/books/wiley-book-style/</guid>
      <description>The Wiley Book Style Description: The Wiley Publishing Company provides two templates for authors wishing to use LaTeX to supply their books for typesetting. The difference between the two templates is purely in their dimensions, one is for 6″ x 9″ books while the other is for 7″ x 10″ books. The templates include all features required for book publication: title page, copyright page, dedication, contributors list, table of contents/figures/tables, acronyms, glossary, symbols, parts, chapters, appendices, references and an index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thin Formal Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/formal-letters/thin-formal-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/formal-letters/thin-formal-letter/</guid>
      <description>Thin Formal Letter Description: This formal letter template has a narrow appearance pulling the attention of the reader to the minimal amount of text. The layout is very conservative so as to give an air of formality and ample space is left on the bottom of the letter for a signature. Address fields are provided for both the sender and recipient of the letter. The template also features an example of how to add a postscript (P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tufte Essay</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/essays/tufte-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/essays/tufte-essay/</guid>
      <description>Tufte Essay Description This template uses the Tufte class to create an elegant layout for writing essays or other long-form texts. This class features a somewhat controversial wide margin on the right side of each page which is used for: footnotes, margin notes, figure/table captions, citations and even figures and tables themselves. If you are not prepared to make use of this margin or dislike how it looks, it is not recommended to use this template as the class hard-codes its use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tufte-Style Book</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/books/tufte-style-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/books/tufte-style-book/</guid>
      <description>Tufte-Style Book Description: This book template has been designed to conform to Edward R. Tufte’s design style, used in his books and handouts. The most defining feature of this design is the large margin on every page and extensive use of sidenotes. This layout means that the central column of text is uncluttered since further descriptions and citations are housed in the margin. Tufte’s design style does not end there and numerous other typographic and layout tweaks are present in this template and are described in the documentation template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twenty Seconds Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/twenty-seconds-resumecv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/twenty-seconds-resumecv/</guid>
      <description>Twenty Seconds Resume/CV Description: This simple Resume/CV template features a large sidebar with key information about you neatly presented for quick perusal. Your main skills can be quickly highlighted using progress bars ranging from novice to expert, this is particularly useful for programming languages and other skills where time is required for mastery. The template body is then presented delimited by large colored section titles (alternating gray and blue). Inside these, you can further divide content by subsection or simply write paragraphs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University/School Laboratory Report</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/laboratory-reports/university-school-laboratory-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/laboratory-reports/university-school-laboratory-report/</guid>
      <description>University/School Laboratory Report Description: This template provides a clean structured format for writing a report based on a laboratory experiment. The structure follows the typical flow of information required in a laboratory report: the objective of the experiment, methods, data gathered, results and discussion. This template would best suit an student’s write-up of an experiment at a university or school. Original Author: This laboratory book template was originally created by the Linux and Unix Users Group at Virginia Tech Wiki but has been extensively modified for this website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vertical Line Title Page</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/vertical-line-title-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/vertical-line-title-page/</guid>
      <description>Vertical Line Title Page Description: This title page template features a central vertical line which frames the rest of the text on the page. The title is clearly visible in a large bold font and the design also includes a subtitle, author name and publisher information. The title page would be well suited to a book but it can be used for other applications too. The template compiles as a standalone document to act as a starting point for creating a document but it includes instructions for integrating this title page into an existing document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Timetable</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/calendars/weekly-timetable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/calendars/weekly-timetable/</guid>
      <description>Weekly Timetable Description: This calendar template is useful for creating a weekly calendar of recurring events. Within each day, the time of the event is divided from the event title for easy scheduling. This layout would suit a university student planning their weekly lectures, as shown in the example. Important note: The file ‘calendar.sty’ is required to be in the same directory as the template because the .tex file uses this custom style for structuring the calendar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenneker Article</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/wenneker-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/articles/wenneker-article/</guid>
      <description>Wenneker Article Description: This article template features a large eye-catching title section with space for multiple authors and affiliations per author. The article has a traditional two column layout to make content easy to read. An abstract section is present to provide a lead-in or summary of the article and features a large lettrine to further draw the reader’s eye. The template contains examples of sectioning, referencing, equations, tables, figures and lists to make it easy for you to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenneker Assignment</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/assignments/wenneker-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/assignments/wenneker-assignment/</guid>
      <description>Wenneker Assignment Description This template can be used by teachers or students for school or university assignments. It contains a clear title section at the start to specify the assignment class, title, date and teacher/student name. The template supports up to 4 levels of sections to structure the assignment into sections, questions, subquestions and bonus content. Examples of common assignment content are included: figure, equations, lists, table, code and paragraphs of text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenneker Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/wenneker-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/wenneker-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Wenneker Resume/CV Description: This simple and clean Resume/CV template features a two column layout with your most important information displayed in the left column for immediate overview by potential employers. The right column houses the body of the document and begins with a large header containing your name, a subheading for your occupation and a short paragraph detailing your history and/or goals. The rest of the body is neatly divided into main sections with subsections in blue and further descriptions in plain text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wile E. Invoice</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/wile-e-invoice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/miscellaneous/wile-e-invoice/</guid>
      <description>Wile E. Invoice Description This invoice template is for businesses or contractors who need to request payments from customers or clients. It features a clean simple layout with a company name at the top, then a section for the recipient’s contact information, then a section for invoice information, then the invoice items, then a terms and conditions and amount due section and finally a sender’s contact information section. The invoice is created using a series of custom commands that make populating all the information very easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wilson Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/wilson-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:46:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/curricula-vitae/wilson-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Wilson Resume/CV Description: This Resume/CV template features a spacious layout with a conservative style designed to clearly and simply put forward your work experience and information. The layout is most suited to longer CVs as job descriptions can be quite extensive and can be organized with bullet points or paragraphs of text. The inclusion of a personal profile allows you to succinctly state your career goals and achievements while the skills section lets you list large amounts of technical expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a0poster Landscape Poster</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/conference-posters/a0poster-landscape-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/conference-posters/a0poster-landscape-poster/</guid>
      <description>a0poster Landscape Poster Description: This poster features a clean landscape layout with a large header section housing important information about the poster, a column for contact information and space for a logo of your institution or a photo of you. Poster content is neatly divided into four columns to make use of the space available as much as possible. The number of columns can easily be changed if you would like the extra width for larger tables and figures.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>a0poster Portrait Poster</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/conference-posters/a0poster-portrait-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/conference-posters/a0poster-portrait-poster/</guid>
      <description>a0poster Portrait Poster Description: This poster features a clean portrait layout with a large header section housing important information about the poster and space for a logo of your institution or a photo of you. Poster content is neatly divided into two columns which is typical for a poster with a portrait orientation. The number of columns can easily be changed if you would like more room for text. The template features the ability to easily change the color of any section or element and shows this off with several examples (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ACS Publications</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/acs-publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/acs-publications/</guid>
      <description>ACS Publications Description: American Chemical Society (ACS) Publications allows authors to submit their manuscripts formatted in LaTeX to any of their journals. For this, they provide a demo template which contains the structure and reference style they would like for submissions. The demo template provided here includes the achemso class, bibliography style, documentation and an example template with associated bibliography. While the demo template is extensively commented, any additional configuration options you need or problems you may experience are likely to be solved by reading the included achemso.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Geophysical Union</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/american-geophysical-union/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/american-geophysical-union/</guid>
      <description>American Geophysical Union Description The American Geophysical Union (AGU) allows authors to submit their manuscript formatted in LaTeX to any of their journals. For this, they provide a template which contains the structure and reference style they would like for submissions. The template contains two tex files, one for the article and another for supporting information. The AGU LaTeX template features a single-column draft layout by default. The template contains ample commenting which advises you how the AGU would like you to use the template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME)</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/asme/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/asme/</guid>
      <description>American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) Description: The American Society of Mechanical Engineers (ASME) allows authors to submit their manuscripts formatted in LaTeX to any of their journals and conferences. For this, they provide three templates which contain the structure and referencing style they would like for submissions. If you are submitting a journal article for initial review, you should use the two-column journal template; if your journal article has been accepted then you should use the one-column journal template for production purposes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Arsclassica Article</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/articles/arsclassica-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/articles/arsclassica-article/</guid>
      <description>Arsclassica Article Description: This article uses the Arsclassica package (a modification of the Classic Thesis package) to specify the document layout and structure. The template features a single column layout which makes it suitable for a greater number of applications such as for academic articles, business articles and reports. The page layout is very clean and minimal to focus on the content at hand in an elegant way. Examples of virtually all typical article constituents are included: references, mathematics, lists, figures, tables, sections and theorems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Article Notes</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/article-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/article-notes/</guid>
      <description>Article Notes Description: This template is for academics and students wishing to make notes on academic articles for future reference or distribution. It is ideal for long-term preservation of thoughts on any given publication and lets you easily specify the information of the article as well as when the notes were made and last revised. Sections within the template can be populated with your notes on the theoretical background, methods, results and discussion/conclusions of the article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Association for Computing Machinery (ACM)</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/acm-publications/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/acm-publications/</guid>
      <description>Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) Description: The Association for Computing Machinery (ACM) allows authors to submit their manuscripts formatted in LaTeX to any of their journals. For this, they provide templates which contain the structure and referencing style they would like for submissions. For the vast majority of ACM journals, you should use the Small Standard Format Template, however, a few require one of the other templates, so find the journal you are submitting to in the list below to identify the template you should use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Awesome Resume/CV and Cover Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/awesome-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/awesome-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Awesome Resume/CV and Cover Letter Description: This gorgeous Resume/CV template comes with a matching cover letter template to help simplify the process of applying for your next job. Both templates feature a clean header listing your essential contact information and fields of expertise as well as a subtle matching footer. Clear sectioning within the resume/CV template ensures your achievements are easily navigated and extensively described by major heading, then minor heading, then sub-heading.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>baposter Landscape Poster</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/conference-posters/baposter-landscape-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/conference-posters/baposter-landscape-poster/</guid>
      <description>baposter Landscape Poster Description: This poster template features a large header with space for two logos to either side of the title and neatly divides poster content into separate boxes with clear headings in each one. The landscape layout features four columns which can be merged into larger blocks if required, such as in the Results 1, Conclusion and Future Research sections of the template. Merged blocks allow more space for showing off results while blocks taking up one column are ideal for small paragraphs of text or details about the research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>baposter Portrait Poster</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/conference-posters/baposter-portrait-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/conference-posters/baposter-portrait-poster/</guid>
      <description>baposter Portrait Poster Description: This poster template neatly divides content into separate boxes with clear headings in each one. The portrait layout features a small side column for study details and a larger column to show off results obtained from the research. The larger column can be optionally divided into two columns to squeeze more information into the poster. The default colors of the template are in the blue spectrum but can be easily changed within the template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beamer Presentation</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/presentations/beamer-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/presentations/beamer-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Beamer Presentation Description: This presentation template uses the well-known Beamer class and shows how effortless presentation-making with LaTeX can be. The template has examples of most of the features that are typically found in a presentation, including the following example slides: title, overview, paragraphs of text, bullet points, blocks of highlighted text, multiple columns, tables, theorems, verbatim text, figures, citations, references and conclusions/acknowledgments. Examples of how to use sections and subsections show how a presentation can be broken down into distinct pieces for automatic inclusion on the overview slide.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Forces Memo</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/canadian-forces-memo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/canadian-forces-memo/</guid>
      <description>Canadian Forces Memo Description: This template is for producing a memorandum (memo) within the Canadian Forces. It was made by using the Military Writing Guide provided for K. Thomas by his MCpl. Following many terrible experiences of having a memo come back with formatting adjustments required, he decided to come up with a template that will for the most part print a correctly-formatted memo with little need to make tweaks by the user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>Cheatsheet Description: This template is for creating a single page cheatsheet. Cheatsheets act as a reference for shortcuts in an application but can also be used as a reference for commands, symbols, functions, equations and any other use case where there are many ways to do something. The template features a three column layout to pack in a large amount of information into the single page. Each column is further subdivided by headings and blocks of similar commands are separated by spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Equations</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/chemical-equations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/chemical-equations/</guid>
      <description>Chemical Equations Description: This template provides a quick reference for typesetting chemical equations in LaTeX using the mhchem package which has been specifically designed to make chemical typesetting intuitive. The template starts with simple chemical notation and progresses to complex chemical equations involving a variety of interactions and notations. Original Author: The chemical equations in this template come from the mhchem bundle documentation by Martin Hensel. Open this template in SwiftLaTeX</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cies Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/cies-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/cies-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Cies Resume/CV Description: This Resume/CV template features a compact information-rich layout suitable for a mid-career professional. A defining feature of the design is a relatively large block of two-column text at the start of the template to include a summary of interests, achievements, history, etc. This acts as a useful place to communicate information with the potential employer that may otherwise be overlooked by simply reading a list of achievements and job titles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classicthesis Typographic Thesis</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/theses/classicthesis-typographic-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/theses/classicthesis-typographic-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Classicthesis Typographic Thesis Description: This template has been designed as a homage to the elements of typographic style. As such, it has an air of efficiency and optimal design. It is suitable for any high-level degree thesis such as for a PhD, Masters or Honors. Sections within the thesis are clearly separated in a consistent way, as are sections within each chapter. The default structure of the thesis proceeds in the following order: title page, dedication, abstract, publications, acknowledgements, contents, list of tables/figures/listings, acronyms, content chapters, appendices, bibliography, colophon and declaration.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classicthesis-Styled CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/classicthesis-styled-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/classicthesis-styled-cv/</guid>
      <description>Classicthesis-Styled CV Description: This template combines the Classicthesis style with the currvita document layout to create a beautiful CV/Résumé. The margin is moved to the left of the document and now holds employer names, degrees or descriptions which makes for quick reference by potential employers. Major headings are clearly separated as blocks within which each entry is styled with the date, title and description. The template is quite compact and manages to squeeze references and grades for courses into small blocks of text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cleese Assignment</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/assignments/cleese-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/assignments/cleese-assignment/</guid>
      <description>Cleese Assignment Description This template comes in two versions, one for teachers/instructors/educators to create assignments/homework for their students to fill out by hand, and another for students proficient in LaTeX to answer questions posed to them at school or university/college. Both versions contain simple environments for each question and subquestion within, and allow answer boxes to be created with either an answer or blank for space to write an answer. Sets of questions can be grouped by headings and the template includes examples of including an image, table, equation and code within questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Snippet</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/code-snippet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/code-snippet/</guid>
      <description>Code Snippet Description: Often times it is useful to include some code in a document, either as an example or to display it for publication. This template simplifies the process of including code from virtually any programming language in a LaTeX document. It uses the listings package to create a box around a piece of code and allows a large number of well-commented customizations to change its appearance. The template also defines a custom command to include your code from a separate file, making the body of your document much cleaner than if you had pasted the code directly in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compact Academic CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/compact-academic-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/compact-academic-cv/</guid>
      <description>Compact Academic CV Description: This curriculum vitae/resume template is designed to succinctly display your career information and works particularly well for showcasing academic careers. Academics tend to have many appointments, honours and publications which this template compresses down to single lines to maximise readability and minimise length. The design is minimalist with plenty of whitespace and a central feature of the template is the optional year labels for all entries in the CV.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Compact Laboratory Book</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/laboratory-books/compact-laboratory-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/laboratory-books/compact-laboratory-book/</guid>
      <description>Compact Laboratory Book Description: This template is useful for keeping track of progress made on different experiments in a laboratory. It features a compact layout for clean reading with each day clearly distinct from other days. Multiple experiments and sub-experiments can be cited for each day allowing the tracking of progress on multiple different avenues of research more easily. The template includes examples of a table, figure, equation, bibliography and citation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Booklet</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/conference-booklet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/conference-booklet/</guid>
      <description>Conference Booklet Description This template is for conference organisers who wish to produce a booklet or online document for attendees detailing conference information and presenters. The template is primarily aimed at academic conferences but can be tailored to commercial conferences. The template is structured to initially display a cover page (from image) then the main conference information. A daily timetable follows and breaks down each day into conference events, breaks and talks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference/Event Timetable</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/calendars/conference-event-timetable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/calendars/conference-event-timetable/</guid>
      <description>Conference/Event Timetable Description: This calendar template is useful for creating a conference/event calendar. Each day can be given a title (such as your location on that day) followed by the plan for that day. The calendar can span any number of weeks and the starting dates can be changed. Important note: The file ‘calendar.sty’ is required to be in the same directory as the template because the .tex file uses this custom style for structuring the calendar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contract</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/contract/</guid>
      <description>Contract Description: This template is for creating a contract with static and dynamic content. It is designed such that you add your static contract terms to the template once and re-use it for many clients using a number of dynamic variables, such as for the payee’s name and the hourly rate. The contract terms in this template are for a web design contract and are merely to provide an example of the structure your contract terms may follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Class</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/custom-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/custom-class/</guid>
      <description>Custom Class Description: This template is for advanced users of LaTeX who are interested in creating their own LaTeX class. The creation of a LaTeX class allows one to specify all document requirements (packages, input files, etc) and layout specifications in a .cls file while reserving the .tex file purely for content. An important feature of this template is the inclusion of a pair of custom class options which act as a toggle within the class to change document settings based on the class option supplied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Daily Laboratory Book</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/laboratory-books/daily-laboratory-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/laboratory-books/daily-laboratory-book/</guid>
      <description>Daily Laboratory Book Description: This template is useful for those working in a laboratory where records must be kept for academic or commercial purposes. Often times working in the laboratory means scrawling messy notes in a physical book so this template helps to make a laboratory book more organized and digitally searchable. The template features a cover page, hyperlinked table of contents, daily logs of progress made on individual experiments and a formulae and media recipes section.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Deedy Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/deedy-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/deedy-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Deedy Resume/CV Description: This Resume/CV template features a large header with your name and contact information clearly displayed. The Resume/CV content is then in a two-column layout which concentrates a large amount of information in a small space. This allows you to choose which aspects of your academic and professional life to focus on depending on their importance for the position you are applying for. Major sections and their subsections are strongly deviated to grab the attention of the hiring manager.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Developer CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/developer-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/developer-cv/</guid>
      <description>Developer CV Description This curriculum vitae/resume template is tailored for software developers to display their skills and experience in a clean and simple way. The top of the template contains space for profiles and contact information on various platforms and uses familiar FontAwesome icons. Skills in various technologies and platforms are displayed at a glance in a skill bar chart and bubbles of varying sizes. Experience at different firms is listed in an ordered list and includes examples of technologies used at each position.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diaz Essay</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/essays/diaz-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/essays/diaz-essay/</guid>
      <description>Diaz Essay Description This essay template is best used for literature essays containing mostly text. This is supported by a thin single column layout with clear unnumbered section titles to increase readability. The template contains an abstract, keywords and references, which makes it suitable for college/university essays but these elements can be easily removed for a simpler high school essay. Further examples of common essay components are included: referencing using a bibliography, an inline figure, a table and lists.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dictionary</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/dictionary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/dictionary/</guid>
      <description>Dictionary Description: This template creates a dictionary with a two-column layout and clear headings delimiting different letters. The header on each page contains the first and last word on that page, making for easy navigation. Converting your current dictionary information to use in this template is easy as a single command specifies the addition of each word. By default, this line has four arguments for the: word, pronunciation, classification and definition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dreuw &amp; Deselaer’s Poster</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/conference-posters/dreuw-deselaers-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/conference-posters/dreuw-deselaers-poster/</guid>
      <description>Dreuw &amp;amp; Deselaer’s Poster Description: This poster template features a dark gray color scheme for content and a contrasting title and footer to highlight important information about the research. Content is laid out in two columns in a portrait orientation but changing it to landscape and increasing the number of columns is quite easy. The template makes extensive use of lists for styling which promotes a clear and concise description of research.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eBook</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/books/ebook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/books/ebook/</guid>
      <description>eBook Description: This ebook template is for those wishing to create a book in a format that is easily readable on electronic screens. To facilitate this, the template features a layout with narrow margins and a large font size to use as much of your screen real estate as possible. Each page features a header with the author and title of the book, as well as a page count at the bottom to indicate progress.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elmueller Formal Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/formal-letters/full-size-formal-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/formal-letters/full-size-formal-letter/</guid>
      <description>Elmueller Formal Letter Description: This formal letter template uses the ‘scrlttr2’ class to structure the letter for mailing with a special section for the addressee designed for windowed envelopes. The letter content is wide and fills the entire page with ample spacing between paragraphs for easy reading. Original Author: This formal letter was originally created by Micha Elmueller but has been extensively modified for this website. Open this template in SwiftLaTeX</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elsevier’s elsarticle Document Class</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/elseviers-elsarticle-document-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/elseviers-elsarticle-document-class/</guid>
      <description>Elsevier’s elsarticle Document Class Description: Elsevier’s elsarticle document class and templates can be used by academics to write and submit journal articles to all Elsevier journals. There are presently over 2,700 journals published by Elsevier with over 250,000 articles published per year. Popular journals include Cell, The Lancet, Lancet Infectious Diseases and Lancet Neurology but a complete list of all Elsevier journals can be found here. Elsevier explicitly state that this class and templates are their preferred format for articles submitted to all of their journals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Calculation Paper</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/engineering-calculation-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/engineering-calculation-paper/</guid>
      <description>Engineering Calculation Paper Description: This template for engineering calculation paper is designed for engineers to present calculations in a clear way for review or documentation purposes. The large header includes meta-information about the document for easy tracking and includes space for a company or university logo. The large main box allows clear presentation of calculations with the aid of sections and subsections. A large margin is present to the right of the main calculations for comments or notes about calculations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fancyslides Presentation</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/presentations/fancyslides-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/presentations/fancyslides-presentation/</guid>
      <description>Fancyslides Presentation Description: This presentation template uses the Fancyslides class which builds on top of the well-known beamer class to give it a modern and concise design. The template is very minimalist with large font sizes and little space for text and would thus be suited for popular presentations by confident speakers. It makes extensive use of background images for slides to provide a strong visual counterpart to the verbal presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>fphw Assignment</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/assignments/fphw-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/assignments/fphw-assignment/</guid>
      <description>fphw Assignment Description This template is for formatting assignments or homework in a clear and simple way. The title section at the top of the first page clearly displays the assignment, student and class information. This information also appears in the headers and footers of subsequent pages. Questions in the assignment are clearly demarcated and appear inside boxes to focus attention. The template features examples of including images, tables, equations and code listings for covering virtually all common assignment information.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Freeman Curriculum Vitae</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/freeman-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/freeman-cv/</guid>
      <description>Freeman Curriculum Vitae Description This curriculum vitae template fits a large amount of information in a concise two-column layout without feeling too saturated with information. When your content grows too large, it will be automatically wrapped to the next page, as you can see in the PDF preview. Sections are cleanly delimited and can be easily moved around to highlight the parts of your experience and skills that are most important to the job you are applying for.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/frequently-asked-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/frequently-asked-questions/</guid>
      <description>Frequently Asked Questions Description: This template provides an easy framework for creating a frequently asked questions (FAQ’s) document. The first page features a large title followed by a subtitle and list of all questions. Questions are clearly displayed in colored boxes with answers after them in plain text. Each question can contain a unique label to allow referencing it in future questions via links. Questions are also automatically numbered and this number can be referred to at any point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Friggeri Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/friggeri-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/friggeri-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Friggeri Resume/CV Description: This beautiful Resume/CV template is suitable for anyone, from a designer with many short contracts to a scientist with varied publications. The template features a sidebar for important information such as contact details, languages, skills, titles, etc. The rest of the content is housed in clear colored sections with each entry featuring a space for a date, title, description and location. The publication list in this template is particularly useful for those that wish to list an extensive list of publications within separate categories.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE)</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/ieee/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/ieee/</guid>
      <description>Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) Description: The Institute of Electrical and Electronics Engineers (IEEE) allows authors to submit their publications formatted in LaTeX to any of their 100+ transactions journals except for IEEE Transactions on Dielectrics and Electrical Insulation. For this, they provide the IEEEtran class and demo templates which contain the structure and reference style they would like for submissions. The IEEE Photonics Society also provides the IEEEphot class and a demo template for submissions to IEEE Photonics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invoice</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/invoice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/invoice/</guid>
      <description>Invoice Description: This invoice template allows a small business or individual to produce invoices for goods and services. It features a clear header including the company providing the invoice followed by the recipient’s information. The list of goods and services being charged for is clear and concise separated by individual days and categories. The ability to include one-off expenses (without an hourly rate) is also present. The template is very simple to fill out; for each line a date, the number of hours worked and the hourly rate are specified and the template does all the calculations to produce the subtotal and total.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jacobs Landscape Poster</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/conference-posters/jacobs-landscape-poster/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/conference-posters/jacobs-landscape-poster/</guid>
      <description>Jacobs Landscape Poster Description: This poster template features a clean sectioned look suitable for presenting research at a conference. Important information is highlighted with colored boxes and each section within the poster is clearly separated from the others. The layout of the template contains four columns but this can be changed to accommodate varying amounts of information or figures. Examples of a table, figure, equation, list and bibliography are present in the template to provide a starting point for any requirement you may have for your own poster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Journal Article</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/articles/journal-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/articles/journal-article/</guid>
      <description>Journal Article Description: This article template aims to emulate scientific journal publications by using a conservative thin document style. The format of the template follows the typical journal publication including an abstract for summarizing the article, introduction, methods, results and discussion. Examples of an equation, table and list are included. Original Author: This article template was originally created by Frits Wenneker but has been extensively modified for this website by Vel.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kaobook</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/books/kaobook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/books/kaobook/</guid>
      <description>kaobook Description This template is designed for writing books and graduate-level theses and provides numerous examples and documentation to enable complex requirements. The design features a relatively narrow main text column with an adjacent wide margin to house notes, figures, tables, citations and captions. The narrow text column facilitates faster reading by reducing horizontal eye movement distance and makes reading less fatiguing. Content can be split into the standard section types of parts, chapters, sections, subsections, subsubsections and paragraphs with examples of all of these provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>kaobook</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/theses/kaobook/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/theses/kaobook/</guid>
      <description>kaobook Description This template is designed for writing books and graduate-level theses and provides numerous examples and documentation to enable complex requirements. The design features a relatively narrow main text column with an adjacent wide margin to house notes, figures, tables, citations and captions. The narrow text column facilitates faster reading by reducing horizontal eye movement distance and makes reading less fatiguing. Content can be split into the standard section types of parts, chapters, sections, subsections, subsubsections and paragraphs with examples of all of these provided.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KOMA-Script Presentation</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/presentations/koma-script-presentation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/presentations/koma-script-presentation/</guid>
      <description>KOMA-Script Presentation Description: This presentation template is unique in that it uses the standard KOMA-Script scrartcl class to create a beautiful presentation. The use of a standard class means that this template allows direct copy/pasting from other LaTeX documents and doesn’t require specialized commands like other presentation classes. The design of the slides is focused on readability with large fonts and line spacing. Each slide features a running head and a footer with information about the author as well as progress through the presentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lachaise Assignment</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/assignments/lachaise-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/assignments/lachaise-assignment/</guid>
      <description>Lachaise Assignment Description This template is for teachers/instructors/educators to create assignments/homework for their students. It includes a clear title on the first page for the course, assignment and teacher’s name, as well as the institution and date. Sets of questions can be grouped by headings and the template includes examples of unnumbered and numbered sections, and numbered subsections (for longer assignments). Amongst the description text for each question, examples are provided for virtually any subject matter, including: equations, algorithms, code and command line outputs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Letter of Notice</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/formal-letters/letter-of-notice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/formal-letters/letter-of-notice/</guid>
      <description>Letter of Notice Description: This formal letter template is specifically tailored to provide a short notice to the addressee. The large heading bar at the top provides a central focus for the letter while the body of the letter is intentionally narrow, centered and in an 11pt font size with increased spacing to restrict the text of the letter to a single sharp message. This template would be most suited to a short formal communication of notice between a client and a business, such as for a notice of inspection, resignation letter or a letter stating intent to move out of a property.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Lined Cover Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/cover-letters/long-lined-cover-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/cover-letters/long-lined-cover-letter/</guid>
      <description>Long Lined Cover Letter Description: This cover letter template uses the newlfm package and features a clean professional layout which can take a large amount of text per page. The ability to include a company/institution logo at the top of the letter further adds to the professional look. The content of the letter itself is presented between two horizontal lines and contains your contact information, the addressee and letter content. Any element of the letter can be easily removed within the template to customize the layout to your requirements.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Long Professional CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/long-professional-curriculum-vitae/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/long-professional-curriculum-vitae/</guid>
      <description>Long Professional CV Description: This curriculum vitae template is clearly structured with bold centered category names for each section. The descriptions of tasks for each job are in bullet points. This template is conducive to longer CVs since there is no aesthetic limit to how much information can be placed in each section. Would suit a professional in the mid- to late-stage of their career. Important note: The file ‘res.cls’ is required to be in the same directory as the template because the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Maggi Memoir Thesis</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/theses/maggi-memoir-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/theses/maggi-memoir-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Maggi Memoir Thesis Description: This template uses the memoir document class to beautifully typeset a thesis. It is suitable for any high-level degree thesis such as for a PhD, Masters or Honors. The layout of the content is in a thin format to promote easy reading and the template features advanced specification of margins and trimming. An example of this is seen in the trimming lines within the preview for this template whereby the stock paper size and the size of the content are independently specified within the template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Masters/Doctoral Thesis</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/theses/masters-doctoral-thesis/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/theses/masters-doctoral-thesis/</guid>
      <description>Masters/Doctoral Thesis Description This template provides a full framework for writing a graduate level thesis. It is carefully structured and separated into multiple parts for easy editing. Included are the following pages/sections: a cover page, declaration of authorship, quotation, abstract, acknowledgements, contents page(s), list of figures, list of tables, abbreviations, physical constants, symbols, dedication, example chapter, example appendix and bibliography. An example chapter is included which explains the basics of LaTeX and this template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medium Length Graduate CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/medium-length-graduate-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/medium-length-graduate-cv/</guid>
      <description>Medium Length Graduate CV Description: This curriculum vitae template has section headings on the left side of the document with section content on the right. Bullet points are used to separate different tasks within each job. This document layout makes this template more suited to a short or medium length curriculum vitae taking at most two pages. Would be best used by a recent graduate with limited experience looking for their first job.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Medium Length Professional</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/medium-length-professional-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/medium-length-professional-cv/</guid>
      <description>Medium Length Professional Description: This curriculum vitae template is clearly structured into sections separated by lines. As is, the template is more conducive to medium-length professional CV’s where work experience dominates the interest of the employer. The template can easily be expanded out to multiple pages but is best kept to at most 2 pages for section clarity. Important note: The file ‘resume.cls’ is required to be in the same directory as the template because the .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memo</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/memo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/memo/</guid>
      <description>Memo Description: A memo (formal name memorandum) is a business document used for communication within a company or between two companies. Their purpose is to convey information in a relatively short but formal document which can be sent out to a number of relevant people. This template uses the texMemo class to make writing a memo using LaTeX incredibly simple. The template includes the ability to include a company logo underneath which the memo information is housed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ModernCV and Cover Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/moderncv-cv-and-cover-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/moderncv-cv-and-cover-letter/</guid>
      <description>ModernCV and Cover Letter Description: This template uses the ‘ModernCV’ class to create a multi-page CV and cover letter. The CV is clearly structured with large section titles and important dates on a sidebar. Contact information is clearly displayed in a gray block. This class features four document themes which completely change the layout of the document, to get a preview of each of these themes see the PDF previews below.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Monthly Calendar</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/calendars/monthly-calendar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/calendars/monthly-calendar/</guid>
      <description>Monthly Calendar Description: This calendar template is useful for creating a calendar month on a single A4 sheet of paper. This can be left blank with just the day numbers or text can be written for individual days. The starting day and date can be readily changed within the template. LaTeX is not made for easily numbering calendars and automatically adjusting to different needs. This means this template can be a bit finicky but it has been extensively commented to make it as easy as possible to use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIH Grant Proposal</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/nih-grant-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/nih-grant-proposal/</guid>
      <description>NIH Grant Proposal Description: The National Institutes of Health (NIH) provides grants to researchers wishing to fund their research projects. The lengthy application requires a great deal of information regarding the proposed research and this template is meant to make the process easier by creating the document structure required for the application and providing examples of typical content. The template is primarily meant for the Specific Aims, Research Plan and Bibliography sections of the grant application but other parts (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Plain Cover Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/cover-letters/plain-cover-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/cover-letters/plain-cover-letter/</guid>
      <description>Plain Cover Letter Description: A plain cover letter template with your name and address at the top in bold. The layout is traditional and is best suited to single-page letters. The format offers plenty of space for a longer cover letter and includes a description of the content that should be written in each paragraph. Original Author: This cover letter was originally created by the Rensselaer Polytechnic Institute but has been extensively modified for this website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PNAS Journal</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/pnas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/pnas/</guid>
      <description>PNAS Journal Description: The Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences of the United States of America (PNAS) allows authors to submit their manuscript formatted in LaTeX to the PNAS Journal. For this, they provide a template which contains the structure and reference style they would like for submissions. The PNAS LaTeX template features a two-column layout and mirrors the layout seen in final publications released by PNAS. This allows authors to determine the exact length of their manuscripts as they will appear if accepted.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poems</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/poems/</guid>
      <description>Poems Description: This template typesets your poetry in a beautiful and simple way using the ‘verse’ LaTeX package and a number of custom commands. The template is designed for you to quickly typeset poetry without worrying about complex indentation and positioning. Most of the functionality of the package is included in the template including: automatic poem positioning based on average verse length, custom title/author commands, line numbering, every second line indentation, indentation patterns and manual indentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Press Release</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/press-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/press-release/</guid>
      <description>Press Release Description: A press release is a written statement to the media. Press releases are used to announce news, products, services, events, awards, etc. Writing a descriptive press release is a crucial requirement of PR and communication work. This template makes writing a press release easy by dividing the document into the necessary sections and elements that are required for a clear press release. At the top of the press release is a place for a logo for your company/institution which serves to give the release credibility and recognition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional Formal Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/formal-letters/professional-formal-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/formal-letters/professional-formal-letter/</guid>
      <description>Professional Formal Letter Description: This formal letter template is suitable for individuals representing a professional institution such as a university, company or organization. This is most evident in the large header at the top of the letter where there is space for a logo and a large institution name along with your name and title. A block for your information is neatly tucked away underneath the header line on the right with a vertically-overlapping block for the addressee information underneath on the left.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/newsletters/professional-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/newsletters/professional-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>Professional Newsletter Description: This elegant newsletter template is best suited to corporate or organizational newsletters with several large entries. It features space for a large wide header at the top with the company logo and information. The layout is highly modifiable and features the ability to include a sidebar encased in a border, an in-text box, quotation and single or multi-column text layouts in any configuration! The template makes extensive use of linking for quick reader browsing, a table of contents is present on the first page and links to every entry in the newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional Table</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/professional-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/professional-table/</guid>
      <description>Professional Table Description: This table template provides a quick reference for how to add professional-looking tables to any document. The booktabs package is utilized to enable the use of horizontal rules specific for different parts of the table, adding to the overall professional aesthetic of the table. The table includes examples of amalgamating multiple columns into one cell and creating horizontal rules which do not span the entire width of the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Public Library of Science (PLOS)</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/public-library-of-science-plos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/public-library-of-science-plos/</guid>
      <description>Public Library of Science (PLOS) Description: The Public Library of Science (PLOS) allows authors to submit their manuscript formatted in LaTeX to any of their journals. For this, they provide a template which contains the structure and reference style they would like for submissions. Journals published by PLOS include: PLOS ONE, PLOS Biology, PLOS Medicine, PLOS Computational Biology, PLOS Genetics, PLOS Pathogens, PLOS Neglected Tropical Diseases and PLOS Currents. The PLOS LaTeX template features an intentionally simple layout to make review easy and PLOS explicitly state that template elements should not be modified or removed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Royal Society of Chemistry</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/royal-society-of-chemistry/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/royal-society-of-chemistry/</guid>
      <description>Royal Society of Chemistry Description The Royal Society of Chemistry provides two LaTeX templates for authors to submit articles and communications to all journals they publish. Each template includes dummy content which provides an example for authors for how to write their paper in LaTeX. At the submission stage, author(s) are requested to provide a PDF of the manuscript typeset in LaTeX including all figures as well as the LaTeX files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Science Journal</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/science-journal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/academic-journals/science-journal/</guid>
      <description>Science Journal Description: The Science Journal allows authors to submit their manuscripts formatted in LaTeX. For this, they provide a template which contains the structure and reference style they would like for submissions. The template provided here includes a filled-out example article, the Science bibliography style, example bibliography and the scicite package used for formatting the reference numbers. The template is extensively commented and sectioned to make writing your Science manuscript easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Stylish Cover Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/cover-letters/short-stylish-cover-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/cover-letters/short-stylish-cover-letter/</guid>
      <description>Short Stylish Cover Letter Description: This stylish cover letter includes a custom large header and footer. The ‘To’ address is placed so as to show up in a windowed envelope. Unfortunately these do not leave much space for text but there are several ways of increasing available space described in the template. Important notes: this template needs to be compiled with XeLaTeX. There should be a setting in your LaTeX distribution to change to XeLaTeX.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Short Three Column Newsletter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/newsletters/short-three-column-newsletter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/newsletters/short-three-column-newsletter/</guid>
      <description>Short Three Column Newsletter Description: This newsletter template is best suited to shorter newsletters consisting of short articles from a number of contributors. It features a prominent main news item at the start to provide a space for important updates or a summation of events by a single author. The body of the newsletter has a three-column layout which is conducive to short articles by a number of authors. The newsletter header on the first page clearly displays the newsletter name and edition while the footers on each page provide contact information and a longer description of the newsletter.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stylish Article</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/articles/stylish-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/articles/stylish-article/</guid>
      <description>Stylish Article Description: This article template attempts to emulate the design of contemporary scientific publications. It does this by including colored boxes behind the abstract and headings and a succinct text layout. The template features a table of contents, something usually not seen in articles, which makes it ideal for longer articles with significant structure or for archival purposes. This table of contents can be removed for a look more suited to journal publication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Legrand Orange Book</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/books/the-legrand-orange-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/books/the-legrand-orange-book/</guid>
      <description>The Legrand Orange Book Description: This book template features an elegant layout with a beautiful title page and part/chapter headings. The book itself is highly structured into parts, chapters, sections and then subsections. Each is numbered and these numbers are prominently displayed in the left margin where each begins as well as in page headers. Sections and subsections also appear as mini tables of contents on pages separating parts of the book to provide an outline of the content to come.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Wiley Book Style</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/books/wiley-book-style/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/books/wiley-book-style/</guid>
      <description>The Wiley Book Style Description: The Wiley Publishing Company provides two templates for authors wishing to use LaTeX to supply their books for typesetting. The difference between the two templates is purely in their dimensions, one is for 6″ x 9″ books while the other is for 7″ x 10″ books. The templates include all features required for book publication: title page, copyright page, dedication, contributors list, table of contents/figures/tables, acronyms, glossary, symbols, parts, chapters, appendices, references and an index.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Thin Formal Letter</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/formal-letters/thin-formal-letter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/formal-letters/thin-formal-letter/</guid>
      <description>Thin Formal Letter Description: This formal letter template has a narrow appearance pulling the attention of the reader to the minimal amount of text. The layout is very conservative so as to give an air of formality and ample space is left on the bottom of the letter for a signature. Address fields are provided for both the sender and recipient of the letter. The template also features an example of how to add a postscript (P.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tufte Essay</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/essays/tufte-essay/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/essays/tufte-essay/</guid>
      <description>Tufte Essay Description This template uses the Tufte class to create an elegant layout for writing essays or other long-form texts. This class features a somewhat controversial wide margin on the right side of each page which is used for: footnotes, margin notes, figure/table captions, citations and even figures and tables themselves. If you are not prepared to make use of this margin or dislike how it looks, it is not recommended to use this template as the class hard-codes its use.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tufte-Style Book</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/books/tufte-style-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/books/tufte-style-book/</guid>
      <description>Tufte-Style Book Description: This book template has been designed to conform to Edward R. Tufte’s design style, used in his books and handouts. The most defining feature of this design is the large margin on every page and extensive use of sidenotes. This layout means that the central column of text is uncluttered since further descriptions and citations are housed in the margin. Tufte’s design style does not end there and numerous other typographic and layout tweaks are present in this template and are described in the documentation template.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Twenty Seconds Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/twenty-seconds-resumecv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/twenty-seconds-resumecv/</guid>
      <description>Twenty Seconds Resume/CV Description: This simple Resume/CV template features a large sidebar with key information about you neatly presented for quick perusal. Your main skills can be quickly highlighted using progress bars ranging from novice to expert, this is particularly useful for programming languages and other skills where time is required for mastery. The template body is then presented delimited by large colored section titles (alternating gray and blue). Inside these, you can further divide content by subsection or simply write paragraphs.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>University/School Laboratory Report</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/laboratory-reports/university-school-laboratory-report/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/laboratory-reports/university-school-laboratory-report/</guid>
      <description>University/School Laboratory Report Description: This template provides a clean structured format for writing a report based on a laboratory experiment. The structure follows the typical flow of information required in a laboratory report: the objective of the experiment, methods, data gathered, results and discussion. This template would best suit an student’s write-up of an experiment at a university or school. Original Author: This laboratory book template was originally created by the Linux and Unix Users Group at Virginia Tech Wiki but has been extensively modified for this website.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Weekly Timetable</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/calendars/weekly-timetable/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/calendars/weekly-timetable/</guid>
      <description>Weekly Timetable Description: This calendar template is useful for creating a weekly calendar of recurring events. Within each day, the time of the event is divided from the event title for easy scheduling. This layout would suit a university student planning their weekly lectures, as shown in the example. Important note: The file ‘calendar.sty’ is required to be in the same directory as the template because the .tex file uses this custom style for structuring the calendar.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenneker Article</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/articles/wenneker-article/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/articles/wenneker-article/</guid>
      <description>Wenneker Article Description: This article template features a large eye-catching title section with space for multiple authors and affiliations per author. The article has a traditional two column layout to make content easy to read. An abstract section is present to provide a lead-in or summary of the article and features a large lettrine to further draw the reader’s eye. The template contains examples of sectioning, referencing, equations, tables, figures and lists to make it easy for you to get started.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenneker Assignment</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/assignments/wenneker-assignment/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/assignments/wenneker-assignment/</guid>
      <description>Wenneker Assignment Description This template can be used by teachers or students for school or university assignments. It contains a clear title section at the start to specify the assignment class, title, date and teacher/student name. The template supports up to 4 levels of sections to structure the assignment into sections, questions, subquestions and bonus content. Examples of common assignment content are included: figure, equations, lists, table, code and paragraphs of text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wenneker Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/wenneker-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/wenneker-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Wenneker Resume/CV Description: This simple and clean Resume/CV template features a two column layout with your most important information displayed in the left column for immediate overview by potential employers. The right column houses the body of the document and begins with a large header containing your name, a subheading for your occupation and a short paragraph detailing your history and/or goals. The rest of the body is neatly divided into main sections with subsections in blue and further descriptions in plain text.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wile E. Invoice</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/wile-e-invoice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/miscellaneous/wile-e-invoice/</guid>
      <description>Wile E. Invoice Description This invoice template is for businesses or contractors who need to request payments from customers or clients. It features a clean simple layout with a company name at the top, then a section for the recipient’s contact information, then a section for invoice information, then the invoice items, then a terms and conditions and amount due section and finally a sender’s contact information section. The invoice is created using a series of custom commands that make populating all the information very easy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wilson Resume/CV</title>
      <link>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/wilson-resume-cv/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 05:28:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://swiftlatex.github.io/LaTeXBoilerPlate/posts/title-pages/curricula-vitae/wilson-resume-cv/</guid>
      <description>Wilson Resume/CV Description: This Resume/CV template features a spacious layout with a conservative style designed to clearly and simply put forward your work experience and information. The layout is most suited to longer CVs as job descriptions can be quite extensive and can be organized with bullet points or paragraphs of text. The inclusion of a personal profile allows you to succinctly state your career goals and achievements while the skills section lets you list large amounts of technical expertise.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>