<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>title-pages on LaTeX Boilerplates</title>
    <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/tags/title-pages/</link>
    <description>Recent content in title-pages on LaTeX Boilerplates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.swiftlatex.org/tags/title-pages/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Academic Title Page</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/title-pages/academic-title-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/title-pages/academic-title-page/</guid>
      <description>Academic Title Page Description: This title page is useful for academic works such as assignments, reports, theses or books. The headings can be used to neatly display the institute, course or subject matter of the work. It design is clean with the major feature being two horizontal lines highlighting the title. The template contains code for an alternate layout without a supervisor name and for an institution logo at the bottom of the page.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Classic Lined Title Page</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/title-pages/classic-lined-title-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/title-pages/classic-lined-title-page/</guid>
      <description>Classic Lined Title Page Description: This title page template features a classic lined look most suited to a book or other larger work. The title is highlighted with large red all-caps text and a thin rule underneath separates it from the author name and publisher further down the page. For a less intense look, a diversity of colours are available for selection, see here for a full list with examples. The template compiles as a standalone document to act as a starting point for creating a document but it includes instructions for integrating this title page into an existing document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Formal Book Title Page</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/title-pages/formal-book-title-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/title-pages/formal-book-title-page/</guid>
      <description>Formal Book Title Page Description: This title page template is best suited to books and formal applications, such as in the fields of science or engineering. It features a formal layout with a clear title highlighted by two horizontal rules. A subtitle is available to further describe the work and multiple authors/editors are catered for towards the centre of the page. The template compiles as a standalone document to act as a starting point for creating a document but it includes instructions for integrating this title page into an existing document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Minimalist Book Title Page</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/title-pages/minimalist-book-title-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/title-pages/minimalist-book-title-page/</guid>
      <description>Minimalist Book Title Page Description: This title page template is best suited for a book. The minimalistic design immediately highlights the title and the use of red further focuses the eye on the core of what the work is about. The subtitle is neatly tucked away under the title to expand on it and the author/publisher information frames the title. A diversity of colours are available for the title, see here for a full list with examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Purpose Large Font</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/title-pages/multi-purpose-large-font-title-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/title-pages/multi-purpose-large-font-title-page/</guid>
      <description>Multi-Purpose Large Font Description: This title page template can be used for almost any document type. The title is displayed in a very large font size in a wide grey box to accentuate the subject matter while your details are shown at the bottom in a small section. The box colour can be changed from grey and the template includes a secondary serif font option. This template compiles as a standalone document to act as a starting point for creating a document but it includes instructions for integrating the title page into an existing document.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stylish Title Page</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/title-pages/stylish-title-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/title-pages/stylish-title-page/</guid>
      <description>Stylish Title Page Description: This title page template features a large title and subtitle surrounded by two curly brackets to bring focus to the title and add to the stylish design of the template. The author name is centered below the title and publisher information is seen at the bottom. This makes the template best suited to a book or other large work, but it can be easily adapted to any other usage.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Vertical Line Title Page</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/title-pages/vertical-line-title-page/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/title-pages/vertical-line-title-page/</guid>
      <description>Vertical Line Title Page Description: This title page template features a central vertical line which frames the rest of the text on the page. The title is clearly visible in a large bold font and the design also includes a subtitle, author name and publisher information. The title page would be well suited to a book but it can be used for other applications too. The template compiles as a standalone document to act as a starting point for creating a document but it includes instructions for integrating this title page into an existing document.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>