<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>miscellaneous on LaTeX Boilerplates</title>
    <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/tags/miscellaneous/</link>
    <description>Recent content in miscellaneous on LaTeX Boilerplates</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.swiftlatex.org/tags/miscellaneous/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Article Notes</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/article-notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/article-notes/</guid>
      <description>Article Notes Description: This template is for academics and students wishing to make notes on academic articles for future reference or distribution. It is ideal for long-term preservation of thoughts on any given publication and lets you easily specify the information of the article as well as when the notes were made and last revised. Sections within the template can be populated with your notes on the theoretical background, methods, results and discussion/conclusions of the article.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Canadian Forces Memo</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/canadian-forces-memo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/canadian-forces-memo/</guid>
      <description>Canadian Forces Memo Description: This template is for producing a memorandum (memo) within the Canadian Forces. It was made by using the Military Writing Guide provided for K. Thomas by his MCpl. Following many terrible experiences of having a memo come back with formatting adjustments required, he decided to come up with a template that will for the most part print a correctly-formatted memo with little need to make tweaks by the user.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cheatsheet</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/cheatsheet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/cheatsheet/</guid>
      <description>Cheatsheet Description: This template is for creating a single page cheatsheet. Cheatsheets act as a reference for shortcuts in an application but can also be used as a reference for commands, symbols, functions, equations and any other use case where there are many ways to do something. The template features a three column layout to pack in a large amount of information into the single page. Each column is further subdivided by headings and blocks of similar commands are separated by spaces.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chemical Equations</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/chemical-equations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/chemical-equations/</guid>
      <description>Chemical Equations Description: This template provides a quick reference for typesetting chemical equations in LaTeX using the mhchem package which has been specifically designed to make chemical typesetting intuitive. The template starts with simple chemical notation and progresses to complex chemical equations involving a variety of interactions and notations. Original Author: The chemical equations in this template come from the mhchem bundle documentation by Martin Hensel. Open this template in SwiftLaTeX</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code Snippet</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/code-snippet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/code-snippet/</guid>
      <description>Code Snippet Description: Often times it is useful to include some code in a document, either as an example or to display it for publication. This template simplifies the process of including code from virtually any programming language in a LaTeX document. It uses the listings package to create a box around a piece of code and allows a large number of well-commented customizations to change its appearance. The template also defines a custom command to include your code from a separate file, making the body of your document much cleaner than if you had pasted the code directly in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conference Booklet</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/conference-booklet/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/conference-booklet/</guid>
      <description>Conference Booklet Description This template is for conference organisers who wish to produce a booklet or online document for attendees detailing conference information and presenters. The template is primarily aimed at academic conferences but can be tailored to commercial conferences. The template is structured to initially display a cover page (from image) then the main conference information. A daily timetable follows and breaks down each day into conference events, breaks and talks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contract</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/contract/</guid>
      <description>Contract Description: This template is for creating a contract with static and dynamic content. It is designed such that you add your static contract terms to the template once and re-use it for many clients using a number of dynamic variables, such as for the payee’s name and the hourly rate. The contract terms in this template are for a web design contract and are merely to provide an example of the structure your contract terms may follow.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Custom Class</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/custom-class/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/custom-class/</guid>
      <description>Custom Class Description: This template is for advanced users of LaTeX who are interested in creating their own LaTeX class. The creation of a LaTeX class allows one to specify all document requirements (packages, input files, etc) and layout specifications in a .cls file while reserving the .tex file purely for content. An important feature of this template is the inclusion of a pair of custom class options which act as a toggle within the class to change document settings based on the class option supplied.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dictionary</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/dictionary/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/dictionary/</guid>
      <description>Dictionary Description: This template creates a dictionary with a two-column layout and clear headings delimiting different letters. The header on each page contains the first and last word on that page, making for easy navigation. Converting your current dictionary information to use in this template is easy as a single command specifies the addition of each word. By default, this line has four arguments for the: word, pronunciation, classification and definition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Engineering Calculation Paper</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/engineering-calculation-paper/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/engineering-calculation-paper/</guid>
      <description>Engineering Calculation Paper Description: This template for engineering calculation paper is designed for engineers to present calculations in a clear way for review or documentation purposes. The large header includes meta-information about the document for easy tracking and includes space for a company or university logo. The large main box allows clear presentation of calculations with the aid of sections and subsections. A large margin is present to the right of the main calculations for comments or notes about calculations.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Frequently Asked Questions</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/frequently-asked-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/frequently-asked-questions/</guid>
      <description>Frequently Asked Questions Description: This template provides an easy framework for creating a frequently asked questions (FAQ’s) document. The first page features a large title followed by a subtitle and list of all questions. Questions are clearly displayed in colored boxes with answers after them in plain text. Each question can contain a unique label to allow referencing it in future questions via links. Questions are also automatically numbered and this number can be referred to at any point.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invoice</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/invoice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/invoice/</guid>
      <description>Invoice Description: This invoice template allows a small business or individual to produce invoices for goods and services. It features a clear header including the company providing the invoice followed by the recipient’s information. The list of goods and services being charged for is clear and concise separated by individual days and categories. The ability to include one-off expenses (without an hourly rate) is also present. The template is very simple to fill out; for each line a date, the number of hours worked and the hourly rate are specified and the template does all the calculations to produce the subtotal and total.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memo</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/memo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/memo/</guid>
      <description>Memo Description: A memo (formal name memorandum) is a business document used for communication within a company or between two companies. Their purpose is to convey information in a relatively short but formal document which can be sent out to a number of relevant people. This template uses the texMemo class to make writing a memo using LaTeX incredibly simple. The template includes the ability to include a company logo underneath which the memo information is housed.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NIH Grant Proposal</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/nih-grant-proposal/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/nih-grant-proposal/</guid>
      <description>NIH Grant Proposal Description: The National Institutes of Health (NIH) provides grants to researchers wishing to fund their research projects. The lengthy application requires a great deal of information regarding the proposed research and this template is meant to make the process easier by creating the document structure required for the application and providing examples of typical content. The template is primarily meant for the Specific Aims, Research Plan and Bibliography sections of the grant application but other parts (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Poems</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/poems/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/poems/</guid>
      <description>Poems Description: This template typesets your poetry in a beautiful and simple way using the ‘verse’ LaTeX package and a number of custom commands. The template is designed for you to quickly typeset poetry without worrying about complex indentation and positioning. Most of the functionality of the package is included in the template including: automatic poem positioning based on average verse length, custom title/author commands, line numbering, every second line indentation, indentation patterns and manual indentation.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Press Release</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/press-release/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/press-release/</guid>
      <description>Press Release Description: A press release is a written statement to the media. Press releases are used to announce news, products, services, events, awards, etc. Writing a descriptive press release is a crucial requirement of PR and communication work. This template makes writing a press release easy by dividing the document into the necessary sections and elements that are required for a clear press release. At the top of the press release is a place for a logo for your company/institution which serves to give the release credibility and recognition.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Professional Table</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/professional-table/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/professional-table/</guid>
      <description>Professional Table Description: This table template provides a quick reference for how to add professional-looking tables to any document. The booktabs package is utilized to enable the use of horizontal rules specific for different parts of the table, adding to the overall professional aesthetic of the table. The table includes examples of amalgamating multiple columns into one cell and creating horizontal rules which do not span the entire width of the table.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wile E. Invoice</title>
      <link>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/wile-e-invoice/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 23 Jul 2020 04:54:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.swiftlatex.org/posts/miscellaneous/wile-e-invoice/</guid>
      <description>Wile E. Invoice Description This invoice template is for businesses or contractors who need to request payments from customers or clients. It features a clean simple layout with a company name at the top, then a section for the recipient’s contact information, then a section for invoice information, then the invoice items, then a terms and conditions and amount due section and finally a sender’s contact information section. The invoice is created using a series of custom commands that make populating all the information very easy.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>